Guide to the Curtis Dwight Wilbur Papers, 1924-1927
Department of Special Collections
Curtis Dwight Wilbur Papers,
1924-1927
Special Collections M0187
Wilbur, Curtis Dwight, 1867-
.75 linear ft.
Stanford University. Libraries. Dept. of Special Collections and University Archives.
Administrative Information
Access Restrictions
None.
Provenance
Gift of the Wilbur family, 1965.
Biography
Curtis Dwight Wilbur was a lawyer, United States Secretary of the Navy (1924-1929), judge, and chief justice of the California Supreme Court (1922-1927).
Scope and Content
Collection contains various printed speeches and addresses from the period beginning March, 1924 through November, 1927. In addition it contains various newspaper articles and miscellaneous correspondence.
CONTAINER LIST
- Correspondence, 1924: 3/14 -ALS Harriet S. Wells; 4/7 -notarized resignation of Curtis D. Wilbur from the post of Chief Justice of the Supreme Court of the State of California; 10/31 -TLS Ira K. Wells, asst. Attorney-General. (Box 1, Folder 1)
- Correspondence, 1925: 6/4 -ALS Leonard Wilbur. (Box 1, Folder 2)
- Correspondence, 1926:Letters of recommendation in favor of appointing Edwin E. Grant Advising Council to the Prohibition Director, Washington, D. C.; 6/15 -ALS Lyman Wilbur. (Box 1, Folder 3)
- Correspondence, 1927: 11/19 -TL Edwin E. Grant to Jas. A. Johnston, Chairman of the California Crime Commission. (Box 1, Folder 4)
- Correspondence, 1928: 11/16 -TLS Edwin E. Grant; various typed letters of recommendation in favor of appointing Edwin E. Grant to an administrative capacity in the Federal Prohibition Dept.; 6/26 -TLS Paul J. McCormick; 12/6 -TLS John Q. Dille; 7/8 -TLS physical examination report of Sec. Wilbur by C. W. Bunker. (Box 1, Folder 5)
- Correspondence, 1929: 1/11 -TLS Edwin E. Grant; 1/14 -telegram Dr. J. I Campbell; 1/16 -TLS C. M. Goethe; 1/30 -TLS W. S. Norvid; 2/6 -typed memorandum to Sec. of the President; 2/12 -TLS Ralph Arnold; 2/14 -telegram William Howard Gardiner; 2/18 -TLS C. O. Getty to Capt. George F. Neal; 2/18 -TLS Dr. M. Morgan Cloud; 2/19 -ALS Edward C. Downing; 2/23 -ALS Kitty Cheatham with music and poster; 2/23 -TLS R. R. Veale with carbon of reply (TNS); 2/20 -TLS Italian ambassador; 2/25 -TL to Mr. Thomas B. Stoney; 2/25 -telegram James E. Gregg and copy of reply; 2/25 -ALS Mrs. Phillips with part of typed letter to Mr. Booth from H. A. Crane and typed reply from Wilbur's Secretary; 2/26 -copy of telegram sent to Mrs. Fred Paist; 2/27TLS S. T. Montgomery; 3/1TNS Edward J. Henning; 3/1telegrams from Victor E. Shaw, Elvin Swarthout, Billy Rowan, J. V. Jordan, Paul J. McCormick; 3/2TLS John K. Snively; 3/2telegram Marshall B. Woodworth; 3/21telegram Daniel Henderson; 3/30TLS Herman J. Galloway; 3/21telegram sent to S. W. Gramer from Daniel Henderson and telegram to C. W. Wilbur from Daniel Henderson. (Box 1, Folder 6)
- Paper: biographical and re Navy Department (Box 1, Folder 7)
- Address, Thomaston, Mainee, 7/25/?. (Box 1, Folder 8)
- Miscellaneous: 9/30/30article, statement to Chinese friends by a group of Nanking Missionaries, answer to supplemental questionnaire from the U. S. Civil Service Commission. (Box 1, Folder 9)
- Recent Accomplishments in the Navy (Box 1, Folder 10)
- The Navy of the Future (Box 1, Folder 11)
- Memorandum for the N. Y. Times. (Box 1, Folder 12)
- The Navy and Education 5/8/26. (Box 1, Folder 13)
- The Limitation of Naval Armaments (Box 1, Folder 14)
- The United States Navy - a Trade School of Extraordinary Scope. (Box 1, Folder 15)
- article written for Trained Men magazine. (Box 1, Folder 16)
- A Balanced Navy in Saturday Evening Post 5/13/25. (Box 1, Folder 17)
- The Limitation of Naval Armament 5/13/25. (Box 1, Folder 18)
- Training for Navy is Training for Occupations of Civil Life (Box 1, Folder 19)
- Remarks, Y.M.C.A. Banquet, New Willard Hotel, 3/31/24. (Box 1, Folder 20)
- Address, Convention of the Law Enforcement League, Washington Hotel, 4/10/24. (Box 1, Folder 21)
- Address, Republican Women of the District of Columbia, New Willard Hotel, 5/5/24. (Box 1, Folder 22)
- Report of the 9th Annual Dinner and Navy Dinner of the National Security League, Hotel Astor, 5/8/24. (Box 1, Folder 23)
- Address to American Marine Congress at Waldorf-Astoria, 5/15/24. (Box 1, Folder 24)
- Address to American Cotton Manufacturers Association, Atlantic City, N. J., 5/27/24. (Box 1, Folder 25)
- Remarks at conerstone laying of Mercerburg Academy, Mercerburg, Pa., 6/3/24 (Box 1, Folder 26)
- Address to Naval Academy, Annapolis, Md., 6/4/24. (Box 1, Folder 27)
- Report on the Naval Prison, Portsmouth, N. H., 7/11/24. (Box 1, Folder 28)
- Articles on C. D. Wilbur's visit to Chicago. (Box 1, Folder 29)
- Broadcast speech, 8/23/24. (Box 1, Folder 30)
- Address to West Publishing Co. employees, 6/25/24. (Box 1, Folder 31)
- Address to Open Forum Luncheon of Civic and Commerce Associations, St. Paul, Minn., 8/25/24. (Box 1, Folder 32)
- Address at picnic luncheon of Merican Legion Post and Auxiliary, 8/26/24,Jamestown, N.D.. (Box 1, Folder 33)
- Address to Plymouth Congregational Church, Seattle, Washington, 8/29/24. (Box 1, Folder 34)
- Address to Chamber of Commerce, Seattle, Washington, 8/29/24. (Box 1, Folder 35)
- Address to Chamber of Commerce, Bremerton, Washington, 8/30/24. (Box 1, Folder 36)
- Address at dedication of Navy YMCA Building at Bremerton, 8/30/24. (Box 1, Folder 37)
- Address to employees of the navy yard, Puget Sound, Wash., 8/30/24. (Box 1, Folder 38)
- Address to San Francisco Center League of Women Voters, 9/5/24. (Box 1, Folder 39)
- Address to Chamber of Commerce and Commercial Club, San Francisco, 9/6/24. (Box 1, Folder 40)
- Broadcast speech over KPO, 9/6/24. (Box 1, Folder 41)
- Address to navy yard employees, Mare Island, Cal., 9/8/24. (Box 1, Folder 42)
- Address to Optimist's Club, Hotel Biltmore, Los Angeles, Cal., 9/11/24. (Box 1, Folder 43)
- Address to Chamber of Commerce, L. A., Cal., 9/12/24. (Box 1, Folder 44)
- Address at the dedication of the Catholic University Stadium, Washington, D. C., 10/4/24. (Box 2, Folder 45)
- Address at dedication of Salvation Army Building, Georgetown, D. C., 10/19/24. (Box 2, Folder 46)
- Radio address in NYC, 10/20/24. (Box 2, Folder 47)
- Address on Navy Day, 10/27/24. (Box 2, Folder 48)
- Address at Public Mass Meeting in Providence, R. I., 10/29/24. (Box 2, Folder 49)
- Address to Men's Club, First Congregational Church, 12/15/24. (Box 2, Folder 50)
- Address at Lincoln Memorial University 2/12/25. (Box 2, Folder 51)
- Address to Women's Conference on National Defense as Peace Insurance, Washington, D. C., 2/24/25. (Box 2, Folder 52)
- Address at Meeting of National Patriotic Council, New Willard Hotel, 3/6/25. (Box 2, Folder 53)
- Address at Keith's Theater Lenten Service, 3/11/25. (Box 2, Folder 54)
- Address at Conference of Laymen of M. E. Church, Baltimore district, Annapolis, Md., 4/3/25. (Box 2, Folder 55)
- Address at Annual Dinner of Youngstown, Ohio, YMCA, 5/4/25. (Box 2, Folder 56)
- Address to Political Study Club, 5/18/25. (Box 2, Folder 57)
- Address at the Naval Academy, 6/3/25. (Box 2, Folder 58)
- Address at Duke University, 6/10/25. (Box 2, Folder 59)
- Address to All Comers Class, Washington, D. C., 6/14/25. (Box 2, Folder 60)
- Address to First Congregational Church, San Francisco, Cal., 7/12/25. (Box 2, Folder 61)
- Address to National Congregational Council, Washington. D. C., 10/24/25. (Box 2, Folder 62)
- Address to Philadelphia Chamber of Commerce, 10/27/25. (Box 2, Folder 63)
- Address to National Republican Club, NYC, 2/12/27. (Box 2, Folder 64)
- Address to Adult Sunday School Classes, Philadelphia, Pa., 4/30/27. (Box 2, Folder 65)
- Address to Naval Academy, 6/2/27. (Box 2, Folder 66)
- Address to Gettysburg College, Pa., 6/8/27. (Box 2, Folder 67)
- Address at Navy Dept. Exercises, 10/27/27. (Box 2, Folder 68)
- Broadcast speech on WRC. 10/27/27. (Box 2, Folder 69)
- Address to Shadyside Presbyterian Church, Pittsburgh, Pa., 11/6/27. (Box 2, Folder 70)